Hello friends, welcome to a new video all of you.
Today we are going to learn
how to enter car insurance and life insurance in Tele Prime
and also
how to enter maturity of life insurance. Friends,
before starting the video, I would like to
tell you that whoever is visiting my channel for the first
time or
watching the video for the first time, please subscribe to the channel
so that you keep getting
such knowledge videos in future. So
let's start the video.
[Music] First of all,
we will enter car insurance
with
GST. We will press GST.
After pressing GST, we will go to purchase voucher.
After going to A, we will press control plus H here.
After pressing control plus A, change the mode. Look, here the item is
invoice. There is an accounting invoice. There is a voucher. We will go
to accounting invoice. We will select it and enter it.
After entering, we will enter the invoice here. We will
change the date here. We will
change the date here. 5 5 24. Okay, after that we will
give the invoice number here. Okay,
after that we will press Shriram General here.
We have taken insurance from
Shriram General Insurance, okay, we will
check its ledger, we will enter control plus,
after entering control p, see
what is the under group, SD cutter, SD creditor,
okay, under group,
SD creditor, we have created it,
after that we will save it by using control plus a,
after saving we will do it here,
control px a and save it
here also, after saving we will go here,
car insurance,
what will we do here, we will
enter car insurance for car insurance, we will
check the ledger, after checking the ledger, so
what is there here, it is created in Inter-Excess, the
ledger under group is
created in Inter-Excess, we
will save it by using control px a,
after saving, see here, it is an insurance of 7000,
okay, see this here, this option is
coming, press f1 to bring this option,
after pressing f1, see here,
modify tax rate details of GST,
after this we will give yes to this,
after giving yes to this  If we press control and save it, then
this classification nature
tax details of mine which is coming, this option will be
enabled for me. After enabling it,
see here, if we are getting the insurance done from the same state, then
what will we do, purchase tax val
purchase tax, if we are getting the insurance done from other state, then
we will do intra state
purchase tax, okay, if we are doing it
from the same state, then for this we will do purchase tax,
after this here at 18, thereafter
CGST here, after that
SGST here, okay, friends, this is being
told for testing, okay, for such insurance it is
at 28, on 28, on 28, on 28, okay,
CGST SGST, after that we will give the
period period period here, we will give 5 pa 24
to 4 pa 24, we will save it in
accept overwrite back overwrite in right
because it will
not catch any error in my GST table, that is why
we will save it in overwrite  If we save then we will press O,
okay, after that we will
enter the life insurance, if we
enter the life insurance then
we will create life insurance, okay, so here we will do
LIC Jeevan Anand Anand,
you
can put it under group in investment, either you
can put it in capital account capital account
or create drawing life insurance drawing,
under group will go in capital account only,
under group, okay, then we will create life insurance account
under group,
we will
save it, we will pay the premium,
my date of depositing the premium is on 10th, not
6th, sorry, it is on 6th,
so we will press here also,
after pressing also we will go to payment voucher
f5, so here Jeevan Anand
Jeevan Anand how much 3000 are we paying,
okay, after that it will be credited here, if we are
doing it from the bank then
we will save it, after that we will
enter its maturity, before entering the match
we will check its
effect on the capital account, so
in the capital account  Let's go and see, the live drawing has come,
Jeevan Anand, you can enter it in investment also, you can
create an under group in investment, okay, so
after that we will
press and enter the maturity,
press to do this,
after pressing we will go to 'A' on 'Y', after going to 'R' in 'R',
see here we will change the date on LIC Jeevan Anand,
this way it is for 10 years, 15 years,
whatever the premium is, okay, so here we will make it
10 pa, friends, for testing, we are
telling you, okay, here how much will LIC Jeevan Anand
give, the extra amount, which is
my extra amount, the extra
amount that comes from LIC, we will type that
in capital, we will enter capital on '
Y', we will do 'alt plus c' on 'Y', then we will
give capital on 'Y', what will be its under group,
capital account, we will save it on '
Y', suppose 1000 extra came,
1000 extra, after that we will save this on 'Y', bank
IDBI Bank, now we will
check the balance in it, see, we
will check the balance sheet, capital, one
is visible in capital  If there is nothing in this drawing then
friends, in the same way you can enter car insurance and
life insurance.
Friends, please do tell us by commenting how you liked the video
and if you like the video then please like and
share it and if you are new to the channel
then do not forget to subscribe, so we will meet
with a new video. Jai Hind Vande Mataram.